以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将有助于MIT开放课程继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
这是他们主题部分的一部分
that's a part of their subject part of
深入学习，因为我们到达那里，它是
deep learning as we get there and it's
可能是前一天的好话题
probably a good topic for the day before
春假，因为很多人会
spring break because lots of you will
当然看到你会看到
have seen of course you will have seen
样本平均值的平均
the sample mean the average of the of
数据，所以我们有，你会知道
the data so we we have and you'll know
关于预期的意思让我完成
about the expected mean let me complete
什么是预期的意思所以这是
that what's the expected mean so this is
我们所期望的价值X的期望
the expectation of the value X where we
得到x1的概率P1属于X.
get x 1 with probability P 1 belong to X
n概率为Pn所以我们只想要
n with probability P n so we just want
说出我们的平均输出量是多少
to say what's our average out output
平均结果，我们加权
average outcome and we weight it by
他们的概率是P1X1加
their probabilities so it's P 1 X 1 plus
沿加PN×N个所以这是
along plus P n X n so that's the
x的期望值你舒服
expected value of x do you comfortable
用那个符号e，因为那就像
with that symbol e because that's like
到处都有方便的速记
everywhere it gives a handy shorthand
例如，方差是预期的
for example the variance is the expected
什么的价值
value of what
方差是基于预期值
the variance is an expected value based
关于广场的这些概率
on these probabilities of the square of
距离所以每个人都记得它
the distance so everybody remembers it's
涉及广场，这是距离
involves square and it's the distance
从平均而来，所以我让我打电话
from the mean from so I'm let me call
这个状态M也许只是为了拥有一个
this state M maybe just to have a
较小的字母，但我可以这么做
smaller letter but I could put so it's
距平均值减去M的距离
the distance from the mean minus M it's
预期值的平均值
the expected value the average value of
X减去M平方并且一般来说
X minus M Squared and in general of
当然预期这种协方差
course the expected this covariance
矩阵我可以表达任何
matrix I could express with that any
符号，但让我把它拉伸为
notation but let me just stretch it as
至于什么是预期值
far as what would be the expected value
X的任何功能以及我们有着N
of any function of X well we've got n
可能的输出x1到xn我们看f
possible outputs x1 to xn we look at f
x1到xn的f
of x1 up to f of xn
我们等待那些可能性
we wait those by the probabilities that
它们发生了，所以这将让我做
they happen so this would be let me make
这封电子邮件只是一个小角落
just a little corner for this e letter
所以这将是概率
so this would be the probability that
这是f的值的x1倍
that is f of x1 times the value of the
值F在x1所以这是
value F at x1 so this is the
来自x1的可能性和贡献
contribution from the x1 possibility and
现在我们将它们全部包括在内，所以它将是F
now we include them all so it'll be F
X的输出f以概率PN结束
output f of X ends with probability PN
如果X的X是X减去M平方
and if that f of X is X minus M squared
然后我们得到了我们期望的东西，让我
then we get what we expect and let me
记住，所以我只想保留
remember that so I just want to keep
方差去所以这是它的总和
going with variance so it's the sum it's
第一个概率乘以第一个
the first probability times the first
输出减去均方
output minus the mean squared
最后的概率次数
the last probability times that last
输出xn减去M平方
output xn minus M Squared
每个人都应该知道一秒钟
and everybody should know a second
表达第二种做法
expression the second way to do that cut
只是如果我写出来的话就是总和
the sum it's just if I just write out
这些广场，并结合他们一点
those squares and combine them a little
另外，我得到了第二个表达
differently I get a second expression
这通常很有用
which is really useful often a little
更快地计算，所以我可以这样做
faster to compute so can I just do that
这就是X1平方减去2X1
so that's that's X 1 squared minus 2 X 1
M1加M1平方右，然后保存
M 1 plus M 1 squared right and then save
我在这里pnxxn平方减去2xnn
me here pn x xn squared minus 2 xn n
再加上M平了很好
plus M Squared good with it
抱歉加上哦对不起
sorry plus n oh sorry
哦，不，我的意思是我，哦，这只是一个名字
oh no I mean am i oh it's just a name
正确的谢谢你也谢谢你
correct thank you thank you just too
我们该死的好确定可以采取的总和，所以我
damn good ok can we take that sum so I
如果我拿这些，得到P1X1平方
get P 1 X 1 squared if I take these the
第一个人，所以我已经解释了这一点
first guys so I've accounted for this
现在我将减2P1X1M
and this now I'll take minus 2 P 1 X 1 M
所以P1X1M加PnX结束M.
so P 1 X 1 M plus P n X ends M
我只是写出来而且我是
I'm just writing it all out and I'm
要重新组合它，所以现在我有P1M.
gonna recombine it so now I have P 1 M
平方加P2m平方加Pnm
squared plus P 2 m squared plus P n m
平方所以我从P1M得到了什么
squared so what do I have from the P 1 M
一直到PnMSquared平方
Squared all the way up to P n M Squared
你和我在一起所以MSquared是弗里克
are you with me so M Squared is a Frick
在每个学期，所以我会有一个M.
is in every term so I'm gonna have an M
平方，它乘以P1是多少
Squared and what's it multiplied by P 1
这里P2这里Pn我在这里添加它们
here P 2 here P n here I add those up
我得到1就是这样
and I get 1 so that's it
好的，现在我只是简化这件事
ok and now I'll just simplify this thing
所以这是真正的预期值
so this is really the expected value of
我在这里看到了什么
what what am i seeing in this in this
将x约为期望值
term the about the expected value of x
平方
squared right
与X的预期值不同
different from the expected value of X
减去M平方当然这只是
minus M Squared of course this is just
从这里开始的第一个任期，但现在做什么
the first term from here but now what do
我得到这个第二项井
I get for this second term well the
重点是M出来所以这是
point is that M comes out so this is
减去和M和a2以及它做什么
minus and M and a 2 and what it what do
我离开了，所以我已经用完了M我
I have left so I've used up the M I've
用完2P1X1加P和Xn
used up the 2 P 1 X 1 plus P and X n
什么是每个人都应该付出的代价
what's that everybody should just pay
注意这个微不足道我的意思是我们
attention to this trivial I mean we're
只是在这里做高中代数但是
just doing high school algebra here but
但P1X1到P和Xn是M所以我
but P 1 X 1 up to P and X n is M so I
还有另一个MMSquared那里，我
have another M M Squared there and I've
一加上M个平方
a plus M Squared
从最后，所以你看到它
from the end so you see that it is
另一个表达式的期望值
another expression the expected value of
x平方减去M平方代数
x squared minus M Squared just algebra
那就是这个，所以如果
that that is the same as this so that if
你碰巧有一个方便的方法
you happen to have a handy way to
计算
compute
x的预期值平方你
the expected value of x squared you
只会减去M平方而你
would just subtract M squared and you'd
和它一样是的，只是
have the same as this yeah it's just
代数没关系
algebra okay
我可以让我们更深入一点
can i let's let's go a little deeper
如果我能找到它，可以在这里找点东西
with something here if I can find it
有两个很大的不平等
there are two great inequalities in
统计数据和第一个是由于
statistics and the first one is due to
马尔科夫和我不知道你是否知道
Markov and I don't know if you know
马尔科夫不平等它很容易出来
Markov inequality it it comes out easily
事实上我太喜欢我喜欢我了
in fact too easily I like I'm kind of
现在对此讨论感到高兴
happy with the discussion in this is now
我跳到了第五部分
I'm jumped to section five over the book
所以我需要发布第5节
so I'll need to post section 5 which is
概率和统计数据，你会
probability and statistics and you'll
看到这个Markov不等式所以它就是这样
see this Markov inequality so it just
涉及这些东西，这就是为什么我会
involves this stuff so that's why I'll
现在去做吧
go do it now
马尔科夫不平等他是一个伟大的俄罗斯人
Markov inequality he was a great Russian
数学家或大概在1900年和
mathematician or probably about 1900 and
我们将看到马尔可夫链和马尔科夫
we will see Markov chains and Markov
流程是美丽的线性
processes that's beautiful linear
代数但是这个小的不等式是
algebra but this little inequality is
不是它正在玩的矩阵
not matrices it's just playing with
这些但它适用于两个
these but and it applies to two
非负面事件，所以我会赢
non-negative events so I'm gonna win
我应该说所有的X都适用
shall I say applies when all the X all
输出大于等于零
the outputs are greater equal zero so
这将是我要去的
it's going to be a it's gonna I'm gonna
使用这个事实所以它不适用于
use that fact so it doesn't apply to to
类似于高斯的东西，因为它们是
something like Gaussian because they're
高斯输出一路从
Gaussian the outputs go all the way from
减去无穷大和
minus infinity to and
它确实适用于很多
finiti it does apply to a lot of
重要的，简单的，所以我
important ones and simple one so I'm
只是说让我们假设我愿意
just saying let's suppose I would give
这种有限概率的证明
the proof for this finite probability
并且有类似的证据相似
and there'd be a similar proof similar
这里到处讨论
discussion everywhere here
对于连续概率那么做什么呢
for continuous probability so what does
马尔科夫说让我确定我做对了
Markov say let me be sure I get it right
因为我不是一个职业在这个它是
because I'm not a pro at this it it's
自然要估算
natural to want to estimate the
X大于等于的概率
probability that X is greater equals
一些数字a了解什么是
some number a get some idea what's the
X大于等于a的概率
probability of X being greater equal a
所以我们知道什么是肯定的
so what do we know there's a certainly a
数字为0到1之间的数字
number between 0 & 1 that number is
随着增加而变小
going to get smaller as a increases
因为我们将要询问
because we're going to be asking for
更多，如果我采取说两次
more if if if I take a to be say twice
平均值好，是的，我想我接受了
the mean well yeah suppose I take a to
什么是我能做到的两倍
be twice the mean what what so can I
估计概率可能是多少
estimate what that probability could be
这就是马尔科夫所做的事情
and that's what Markov has done he says
但这种可能性是至少在
the probability of that is at least at
最抱歉
most sorry
看我以前至少有一个橡皮擦
see I used to have an eraser at least
对不起，是的，是的，或者更少
sorry at most yes got it is less or
等于平均x-bar是另一种方式
equal to the mean x-bar is another way
写下平均值除以a和this
to write the mean divided by a and this
这是一个或多个的平均值
is this is the mean over a or it's the
在x的预期值，我们可以看到
expected value of x over a we could see
其中任何一个
any of those
符号还可以，正如我们所期望的那样
notations okay and as we expect as a
增加了这个概率
increases the probability this this
数字下降概率发生了
number goes down the probability goes
超过一个，这是一个漂亮的
down of exceeding a so that's a pretty
得到这个概率的简单估计
simple estimate to get this probability
仅就数字a而言
just in terms of the number a which has
进来是因为它是其中的一部分
to come in because it's part of the
问题和我X好吧所以让我
question and the me X okay so let me
举一个例子为等于三好吗
take an example as a equals three okay
所以我要去尝试我会只为
so I'm going to try I'm gonna just for
例子假设a是我想要的三个
example suppose a was three I want to
表明XX的概率
show that the probability of X X being
大于或等于三是没关系
greater than or equal to three yeah okay
所以让我们，我们不知道，我们没有
so let's we we don't know we don't have
如果我们写的话，许多事实都可以使用
many facts to work with so if we write
那些下来我们应该看到原因没关系
those down we should see the reason okay
所以我知道平均值是X的一个
so I know that the mean is a of X so
让我们看看我是否会接受我是的
let's see I'm am I gonna take yeah I'm
例如，让我们采取平均值
gonna for example let's take the mean to
是一个好的所以我会想象
be one okay so I'm gonna imagine that
平均值是一个，我要求的
the mean is one and that I'm asking for
X会变大的机会是什么？
what's the chance that X will be bigger
超过三，我会估计
than three and I'll get an estimate of
三分之一，所以我试图展示
one-third so I'm trying to show to show
X的概率大于等于3
the probability of X greater equal three
小于或等于我说的意思
is less or equal to the mean I'm saying
是一个是三个，所以有更少或
is one a is three so there's less or
等于1/3现在为什么这是真的那样
equal 1/3 now why is that true that's
我有什么表现好我认为是
what I have to show okay I think is that
如果我写下我所知道的，我会看到它
if I write down what I know I'll see it
好的
okay
好吧，让我让我加油吧
all right so let me let me just raise
有这么一点点，我有一个房间
that a little so that I have a room to
写这么知道我知道的
write so what do I know I know the
肉的定义所以我知道X.
definition of the meat so I know that X
1次P1加X2P2加X3P3
1 times P 1 plus X 2 P 2 plus X 3 P 3
让我在这里被带走X5p
allow me to get carried away here X 5 p
5说是我所写的是什么
5 say is is what so what I've written
这是我的假设
down there is the mean and I'm assuming
这是1，所以这是我的事实
that to be 1 so this is the fact that I
知道是1，我想要的是什么
know is 1 and what is it that I want to
证明我想知道的概率
prove I want to know the probability of
更大等于3所以是什么
being greater equals 3 so what's the
概率结果将是
probability that the result will be
大于等于3它是P3所以这是
greater equal 3 it's P 3 so this this is
说P3加P对于那些是
saying that P 3 plus P for those this is
这些是这些概率
these are the probabilities these are
不同的方式，我可能是
the different ways that I might be
更大等于3，我声称
greater equals 3 and I'm claiming that
这个数字少于或等于我喜欢的1/3
that's less or equal 1/3 what I liked
关于这种基本方法是这样的
about this elementary approach is that
我已经说明了这些事实
I've stated these facts these
概率假设和和
probability assumptions and and and
结论直接以数字表示
conclusions directly in terms of numbers
所以我只想表明如果是这样的话
so I just want to show that if this is
那是真的
true then that's true
哦，让我们来看看，我想我在想，
oh let's see I guess I'm thinking that
对不起，我甚至更加特别
the I'm sorry I even took a more special
我正在考虑x1为1X的情况
case I'm taking the case where x1 is 1 X
2是2×3是3×4是4，X5是5
2 is 2 X 3 is 3 X 4 is 4 and X 5 is 5 so
满足我的条件满足
that satisfies satisfies my condition
输出1234或5是
that the the outputs 1 2 3 4 or 5 are
所有马尔可夫马尔科夫只适用于
all Markov Markov only applies when
他们都等于0所以我不得不这样做
they're all greater equals 0 so I had to
拿一个我只是想象这个
take a so I'm just imagining this
特殊情况下可能的输出
special case where the possible outputs
是12345他们的概率是P.
are 1 2 3 4 5 their probabilities are P
1P2P3P4P5平均值为1和什么
1 P 2 P 3 P 4 P 5 the mean is 1 and what
我要表明的是概率
I want to show is that the probability
的大于3小于或等于
of being greater than 3 is less or equal
1/3，你能把这两个放在一起吗？
1/3 and can you put together these two
你能断定这给予我们要
can you conclude given this we want to
得出这样的结论让我退后一步
conclude that let me just step back a
分钟
minute
所以我们知道的就是我们所知道的
so we're what do we know here we know
这是第一行，我们想要证明
this the first line and we want to prove
第二行我们还知道一件事
the second line we know one more thing
所有的概率我们都知道
all the probabilities well we know the
概率加1，我们知道
probabilities add to 1 and we know
他们都等于0，所以让我吧
they're all greater equals 0 so let me
把这些事实在这里也
put those facts in here too
我们知道P1加P2加P3加
we know that P 1 plus P 2 plus P 3 plus
B4加B5是我们知道的1和我们
B 4 plus B 5 is 1 that we know and we
也知道所有的豌豆都更大
also know that all the peas are greater
等于或等于0好吧好吧
than or equal to 0 okay okay
所以我们走了，我想我的想法就是这个
so here we go I think my my idea is this
难道，这就是看三次p3
is this is looking at three times P 3
再加上B4+P5所以我要拿3P
plus B 4 + P 5 so I'm going to take 3 P
3加3P4远离此，所以这将
3 plus 3 P 4 away from this so this will
说P1加2P2加3块礁
say P 1 plus 2 P 2 plus 3 of piece reef
加上第4页以及第5页我只是捡了3
plus P 4 plus P 5 I'm just picking out 3
那些家伙
of those guys
加上我还有一个P4来解释
plus I have one more P 4 to account for
还有两个P5现在给了一个好的
and two more P 5 gives one okay good now
这就是我想要证明的
this is what I'm trying to prove so that
我在这里试图证明这一点
is here I'm trying to prove that this
事情是我想要证明的东西
thing is what am I trying to prove about
这个数字，你很抱歉我在说话
that number and you're sorry I'm talking
很多，但现在我真的来了
a lot but now I've really come to the
指出马尔科夫告诉我的是什么
point what what is Markov telling me
关于那个更少或更少的数字
about that number that's that is less or
等于感谢好吧我正在努力证明
equal to thanks okay I'm trying to prove
这是一个小于或等于一个
that this is less or equal one that's
什么马尔科夫告诉我，但假设它是
what Markov tells me but suppose it was
不止一个
greater than one
你看到问题了吗？
do you see the problem you see why it
不能大于一，因为为什么
can't be greater than one because why
所有其他术语都是更大的等于
all the other terms are greater equals
零
zero
概率大于或等于零
probabilities are greater or equal zero
这些都是更大的等于零和
these are all greater equal zero and the
为了这个，总的东西增加了一个
total thing adds to one so that this
片必须是较小等于所述一个
piece has to be lesser equal the one
这是正确的，是的，所以很多
that's right that's it yeah so a lot of
谈论那里简单的想法，你会看到
talking there simple idea and you'll see
正是这个例子写下来的
the exactly this example written down in
注意没关系然后你会看到更多
notes okay and then you'll see a more
马尔可夫不等式的传统证明
conventional proof of Markov inequality
采取任何简单的不平等步骤
by taking any simple inequality steps
但是在某种程度上更加神秘
but there's somehow more mysterious for
我这是明确的
me this was explicit
好的，所以马库夫chebychev是
okay so that's Markov chebychev is the
其他伟大的俄罗斯可能的名单
other great russian probable list of the
时间和他得到了他的不平等
time and he gets his his inequality so
有两个是马尔科夫
there are the two there's markov
不平等让我再次写下来
inequality let me write it down again
它在这里是马尔科夫不平等
what it was here was markov inequality
关于挫败假设chebychev
on the barkoff assumption chebychev
没有做出这样的假设
doesn't make that assumption
所以现在不能假设输出
so now no no assumption that the outputs
是等于它不现在没事来
are equals it doesn't come in okay now
什么是chebychev试图估计
what is chebychev trying to estimate
好的
okay
让我们转向chebychev，那就是
let's move to chebychev and that's the
最后一个人
last guy
所以他对蒂米·查韦斯感兴趣
so he Timmy Chavez into it interested in
X减去的概率概率
the probability probability that X minus
对我来说，我可以使用它的平均值
the mean M can I use that for me is
可能大于或等于该
probably greater or equal to a the
是一种距离的概率
probability of being sort of a distance
一个从外地开会，以便再次为他们
a away from the meet so again as they
增加我问的更多我问它
increases I'm asking more I'm asking it
远离平均和
to be further away from the mean and the
概率会下降，然后是
probability will drop and then the
问题是我们可以这样估计这个
question is can we estimate this so this
是一个不同的估计，但它是相似的
is a different estimate but it's similar
类似的问题和什么是胖乎乎的
similar question and what's chubby
杰夫的回答这个所以这是
Jeff's answer for this so this is the
这个概率我必须忍受大
probability of this I have to put up big
这一切都是一口气的
that's all one grit one mouthful the
这个X减去M的概率
probability of being that this X minus M
大于等于好，并再次
is greater equal to a okay and again
我们将会有更少或相等
we're gonna have is less or equal to
Sigma平方现在超过了一个正方形
Sigma squared now comes in over a square
所以这是雪佛兰的cheff，我只是采取
so that's Chevy cheff and I just take
今天是时候做这两个因为了
time today to do these two because
他们是它们涉及的分析有
they're they involve analysis there
有基本的工具排序的
there are basic tools as sort of the
如果你是第一件事，你会想到
first thing you think of if you're
试图估计一个概率
trying to estimate a probability does it
适合马尔科夫，只有马尔科夫
fit Markov and it only Markov only
适用所以我将只适用于当放
applies so I'll put only applies when
X都大于或等于零
the X's are all greater or equal zero
这适合chebychev现在我们是
here does it fit chebychev and now we're
采取绝对值，所以我们不是
taking absolute values so we're not
关注X的大小
concerned about the size of X
我们正在与他们保持距离
and we're taking the distance from em so
我们显然是在世界的
we're obviously in the world of
差异我们离他们的距离还可以
variances we're distances from em okay
和chebychev的证据来了
and and the proof of chebychev is comes
直接来自马尔科夫所以我们为什么
directly from Markov so so why we're
要适用马尔科夫这么好的事情
going to apply Markov so good thing that
马尔科夫先来了-现在让我说
Markov came first - now let me just say
这个权利-a-a-一个新的让我打电话
this right - a - a - a new let me call
它这将是一个新的输出和它
it Y this will be a new output and it
将是X减去M平方所以如果我
will be X minus M Squared so that's if I
当然具有相同的可能性
of course with the same probability so
为什么我是x均匀的平方和
why I is x i- m the mean squared and the
相同的概率相同的概率P.
same probabilities same probabilities P
好吧所以我想如果我要申请
okay so I guess if I'm going to apply
我只想接受它需要一个
I'm just going to take that it takes a
明智的，而不是这里的X.
wise here instead of the X's here so and
然后应用马尔科夫，那么什么是X吧，如果
then apply Markov so what is X bar so if
我想申请Markov我必须要想
I want to apply Markov I have to figure
在这里我必须得到X的平均值
out the mean of X over here I have to
弄清楚Y的意思是
figure out the mean of Y what is the
的Y指的是平均值的总和
mean of Y the mean value the sum of
概率x明智
probabilities x wise
你应该认识到这是
you're supposed to recognize it this is
概率和我的y的总和
the sum of probabilities and my y's are
xi减去均方，所以这个
the x i minus the mean squared so this
这就是这件事的意思
is the mean for this this this y thing
我带来的是那个公式
that I've brought in has that formula
我们认识到这个数量是多少
and we recognize what that quantity is
这就是西格玛平方西格玛的平方
that is that Sigma squared Sigma squared
对于原始X来说就是这样
for the original X's so that's just
这是非常大，所以平均是西格玛是
that's great so the mean is Sigma is the
老西格玛广场那些感叹
old Sigma square those are exclamation
标记好，所以我现在看到了
marks okay so then I do you see that now
马尔科夫看起来像或chebychev是
Markov is looking like or chebychev is
看起来像马尔科夫，因为在这里
looking like Markov because here over
这里将是我现在想要的X.
here will be the X now I want the
y的期望值超过让我们看看是的
expected value of y over let's see yep
所以预期的Y就是这样
so the expected Y is going to be that
现在我有什么要分开的呢
and now what do I have to divide by I
想知道某事的可能性
want to know probabilities of something
这个东西越大越大
being bigger of this thing being bigger
不是现在，但我看在Y的这样
than a but now I'm looking at the Y's so
如果X减去M的概率是
the probability of if X minus M is
大于或等于然后X减去
greater than or equal to a then X minus
XI减去MSquared大于等于a
X I minus M Squared is greater equal a
平方如此，所以我在这里为我做了一个
squared so so I my my a over here for X
我现在正在解决这个问题
is now turning in this problem where I'm
看起来概率大于等于a
looking a probability greater equal a
但是，这就是a
but squaring it this the is the a
平方
squared
所以马克夫在这里适用于Y.
so that's Markov applied to Y here's
马尔科夫应用于X和X必须是
Markov applied to X and X had to be
更大等于零
greater equals zero
所以在这里chebychev拿了一个Y.
so over here chebychev took a Y which
那么大于等于零
was greater equals zero then just
应用马尔可夫并认识到了什么
applied Markov and recognized that what
平均值是他的变量Xmy
that the mean was of his variable X my
我的X减去MSquared就是西格玛
my X minus M Squared was exactly Sigma
平方而且它再次掉出来了
squared and it fell out so again here is
马尔科夫的一个非常简单的证明然后
a very simple proof for Markov and then
每个人都同意chebychev跟随
everybody agrees that chebychev follows
马克诺夫马克，所以那些
right away from Markov ok so those are
现在另一个是两个基本的不平等
two basic inequalities now the other
话题，我想处理是
topic that I wanted to to deal with was
你必须的协方差协方差矩阵
covariance covariance matrix you have to
变得舒服或者那是什么
get like comfortable or what is that
什么是协方差好的
what's the covariance okay
[掌声]
[Applause]
所以协方差协方差矩阵和它
so covariance covariance matrix and it
当我有MM的时候，M将是M.
will be M by M when I have M M sort of
实验M立刻让我带走了我
experiments M at once let me take a me
把两个你放在一起你会看到一切
put the two you you'll see everything
对于m等于2，所以这是我们的
for m equal to two so it's a we're
预计由两个矩阵得到两个
expecting to get a two by two matrix and
我们从什么开始，我们开始我们
what are we starting with we start we're
我们一次做两个实验
doing two experiments at once so we have
两个输出两个输出X和y
two outputs two outputs an X and the y
所以X是X的输出
so the X's are the outputs from the X
实验Y是输出
experiment the Y's are the output from
来自第二次实验我们是
the from a second experiment we're
翻转两个硬币让我们接受
flipping two coins so let's take that
例如两个硬币硬币一个零或
example two coins coin one gets zero or
一个人的概率1/2硬币到
one with people probability 1/2 coin to
0或1，概率为1/2，所以他们是
0 or 1 with probability 1/2 so they're
公平的硬币，但我没有说的是
fair coins but what I haven't said is
两者之间是否存在联系？
are there is there a connection between
输出这是X这是Y.
the output this is the X this is the Y
如果我将硬币粘在一起，那么
is if I glue the coins together then the
我认为这两个输出是一样的
two outputs are the same I think this
对我来说，这是一个模型问题
for me this is a model question that
揭示了协方差的主要观点
brings out the main point of covariance
如果我分开翻转两个硬币
if I flip two coins separately quite
独立然后没有
independently then there's no
[音乐]
[Music]
我不能不知道为什么来自
I can't I don't know more about why from
知道X，如果我知道一个人的答案
knowing X if I know the answer to one
翻转它并没有告诉我任何事情
flip it doesn't tell me anything about
第二个如果他们是独立的
the second if they're independent
不相关，但如果两个硬币是
uncorrelated but if the two coins are
粘在一起，然后头，所以上来
glued together then heads so come up for
两个硬币
both coins
我将只有两个
it'll be I'll only have two
可能是头脑或头脑的可能性
possibilities that'll be heads heads or
尾巴让我让我写下来
tails tails let me let me write down
有两种不同的情景
that there was two different scenarios
如此脱胶，我从没想过要写
so unglued I never expected to write
数学课上的那个词，我是什么
that word in a math class and what am I
写下来我要写
going to write down I'm going to write
向下一个带有硬币头尾的矩阵
down a matrix with heads tails for coin
1和硬币2的头和尾，所以
1 and heads and tails for coin 2 so the
可能性是硬币得到的头
possibilities are coin one gets heads
而第二点得到的是什么
and point two gets heads what's the
这是脱胶的概率
probability of that this is the unglued
案件所以我要创造一点
case so I'm gonna create a little
关节概率矩阵
probability matrix of joint
概率这是真正的关键词
probabilities that's really the key word
你是的，我在这里讨论
that you yeah that I'm discussing here
联合概率让我们完成
joint probabilities so let's complete
那个矩阵所以我有脱胶硬币
that matrix so I have unglued coins
独立的硬币我把它们翻了个什么
independent coins I flip them both what
获得成功的机会是什么？
what is the chances of getting heads on
两者都有1/4的机会是什么
both 1/4 what are the chances of what do
我放在这里
I put in here
这意味着在第一枚硬币和头上
this means heads on the first coin and
第二女王和王后的尾巴
tails on the second Queen and the
那概率为1/4和1/4位置
probability of that is 1/4 and 1/4 here
和1/4在这里所以我有四个
and 1/4 here so I've there four
这是我投入一个2x2的可能性
possibilities which I put into a 2x2
矩阵而不是长矢量我的两个
matrix instead of a long vector my two
头部有四种可能性
four possibilities are heads heads has
尾巴尾巴尾巴尾巴
heads tails tails heads and tails tails
他们有平等的
and they have equal
概率为1/4，但现在如果他们被胶合了
probability 1/4 but now if they're glued
第一个硬币头上的头部和尾部
heads and tails on the first coin heads
在第一个上的第二个尾巴
and tails on the second on the first
硬币头和尾巴在第二枚硬币上
coin heads and tails on the second coin
好吧，现在我放在那里，所以
okay now what do I put in there so the
两个硬币粘在一起是什么
two coins are glued together what is the
他们俩都有可能成为什么样的人
chance that they both come up heads what
如果一个人出现，那就是对了一半
half right one half if one comes up
头
heads
另一种是粘在它它会
the other one is glued to it it will
还有什么是概率
also what what's the probability of
头上的尾巴头上有一条尾巴
heads tails heads on one tails on the
其他当然是零谢谢
other is of course zero thanks
这里是0，这里是1/2，所以我的意思
and here's 0 and here 1/2 so what I've
创造了2个可能加2
created are those 2 possible plus 2
不同的设置两种不同的场景
different setups two different scenarios
脱胶和粘合，在这一个我们
unglued and glued and in this one we
有，但每个每个实验装置
have but each each experimental setup
有它的联合概率矩阵
has its matrix of joint probabilities
这是事情是这样的，有
that's that's the thing that there are
这里有四个数字我们有四个数字
four numbers here four numbers we have
所有的可能性，我们有任何任何
all possibilities we have any any
可能的X和同时任何
possible X and at the same time any
可能Y所以假设我们假设了我们
possible Y so suppose we had suppose we
正在运行三个实验，我们
were running three experiments and we
很好，那会是什么
had well so what would be the what would
如果我跑三个就是这种情况
be the situation if I was running three
用独立的三个实验
experiments with an independent three
独立的公平硬币，所以我有
independent fair coins so I'd have I'd
在这张脱胶的照片中，但我愿意
be in this unglued picture but I would
有三个不同的实验
have three different experiments that
我正在运行什么会是什么
I'm running then what what's what would
我会怎样看待他们
be what would I be looking at them just
整个想法是看看这是什么
the whole idea is to see what is this
像联合概率一样假设我有
like joint probability so suppose I have
三
three
硬币unglue然后我想知道喜欢
coin unglue then I want to know like
有可能获得头脑
some probability of getting heads on the
第一个头在第二个头上
first heads on the second heads on the
第三个就是给我这个
third will be what just to give me that
数字是什么概率
number what will be the probability of
这三个人都是独立的
that all three of them independently
八点好，但现在我的
come up heads one eight okay but now my
问题是，这样我有什么话，我
question is so what do I have then I
有尾巴的概率
have probability of heads of say tails
我们在这里有三个指数
heads heads I've got three indices here
最终降到尾巴的概率
eventually down to probability of tails
每个人在最后看到的尾巴尾巴
tails tails everybody sees at the end of
这些数字将是1/8但是
the numbers are going to be 1/8 but
什么是适合他们的地方
what's the what's where those fit in
它们不适合矩阵，因为我已经
they don't fit in a matrix because I've
这里有三个指数，所以我想是什么
got three indices here so I guess what
我们今天看到我有点意识到了
we're seeing I sort of realized today
我们第一次看到一个张量
we're seeing for the first time a tensor
张量是一种三向结构
a tensor is a three-way structure
三元矩阵你可以这么说我们
three-way matrix you could say so we
我想我想到了这一点
have I guess I think of the of this
而不是像那样的广场
instead of a square like that an
普通矩阵我不得不想到立方体
ordinary matrix I have to think of cube
我有一个带有两个的立方体
right I have a cube with with with two
行两列和Evers
rows two columns and to what Evers
层有人可能会说，为层
layers somebody might say layers for
那你看到的基质
that do you see that the the matrix has
成为
become
一个三通的东西和一个紧张的
a three-way thing a tenser and the
那个缩小的条目，所以它是两个
entries in that tenser so it's two by
两个两个而不是M由n代表a
two by two that instead of M by n for a
矩阵我必须给你数量
matrix I have to give you the number of
行和列数和
rows and number of columns and the
层数进入电路板以便
number of layers going into the board so
以你知道的方式行
rows going one way you know
列行然后是层
columns rows and then layers are going
深，所以我将它会有十
deep so I will that it will have a ten
树，当然在这个简单的情况下
trees and of course in this simple case
每将一个八这在
each will be one eight in this in that
在那个unglue完全独立的方式
in that unglue totally independent way
但是你可以想象一下
but but then you can imagine some
依赖说得好，如果我这样做
dependence say well if I so what would
如果我把第一和第三枚硬币粘在一起，就会发生
happen if I glued coins one and three I
仍然会有一个张量仍然有一个
would still have a tensor still have a
所有的二乘两乘张量
two by two by two tensor of all the
现在的可能性，但其中一些是
possibilities now but some of those are
将有概率为零联合
going to have probability zero the joint
如果我把硬币粘在一起的可能性
probability if I've glued coin one to
然后硬币三的概率
coin three then the probability of
在一个共同的头看到的一切
jointly seeing heads on one whatever on
三个上面的两个尾巴将为零
two tails on three will be zero right
因为如果我坚持下去就不会发生这种情况
because that can't happen if I've glued
硬币一和三，所以我会有八个
coins one and three so I'll have eight
条目在这里的，这是
entries in here in the this is the
脱胶情况，然后我可以有
unglued case and then I could have the
两个硬币是胶水的情况和我一样
case where two coins are glue and as I
说我认为我会有四个
say I think the the I would have four
我可能有四分之一的四分之一
I'd have one quarter four times probably
然后，如果我有任何备用胶水，我会胶水
and then if I had any spare glue I glue
所有三个硬币我翻转卡住了
all three coins I flip that stuck
在一起，我永远不会得到头脑
together thing and I never get heads
尾巴只有我的可能性
tails heads right only possibilities I
让我们的脑袋头顶和尾巴
get our heads heads heads and tails
尾巴因为它们被胶合而尾巴
tails tails because they're glued
那么情况会怎样
together so what would be the situation
三个硬币哦，将是什么
for three coins ooh what will be the
矩阵中关节中的条目
entries in the joint in the matrix of
联合概率将是什么
joint probabilities what will be the
联合概率所以他们的联合
joint probabilities so they joint the
头部头部的概率我已经
probability of heads heads heads I've
从这三个人看到的头将是1/2
seen heads from all three will be 1/2
1/2因为我正在翻转这种沉重的混合物
1/2 because I'm flipping this heavy mix
三个硬币在一起我得1/2两次
of three coins together I get 1/2 twice
好吧，其实我这是一个好人
okay actually I this is a good
以某种方式介绍张量因素
introduction to tensors in a way because
理解的第一步
the the first step in understanding
张量是考虑三向矩阵
tensors is to think of 3-way matrices
想想你了解我们的三方事物
think of 3-way things what you know we
只是没有那样做，现在我们有
just haven't done that and now we have
这样做，当然还有在哪里或
to do it and of course for where or
无论如何，张量现在被理解为好
anyway tensors are now understood okay
所以这些是非常的张量
so this these are tensors with very
特别简单的事情好吧现在我有
special simple things okay so now I have
说什么是协方差矩阵但是
to say what is the covariance matrix but
什么是协方差矩阵，所以现在我
what's the covariance matrix so now I'm
准备好了，我会把它放在这里
ready for that and I'll put it here
那是最后一个话题
that's the final topic
所以我说的是协方差矩阵
so the covariance matrix so I'm saying
矩阵，因为我只是要有
matrix because I'm just gonna have yeah
协方差矩阵是的，它会去
the covariance matrix yeah it's going to
是两个或四个两个硬币所以它是
be two by two or four two coins so it is
它将是一个三个硬币的矩阵
a matrix for three coins it will be
三乘三，但它是一个矩阵没关系
three by three but it is a matrix okay
那么它是如何定义的，我是什么
so what how is it defined and what am I
打电话给我，我想我会称之为V.
going to call it I think I'll call it V
四个因为它真的是关键的想法
for four because it really the key ideas
方差协方差告诉我们
variance covariance is is telling us
我们也对此感兴趣
that we're also interested in the
委员会联合结果x和ay
committee the joint outcome an x and a y
好的，所以这是一个方差，所以我
okay so what so it's a variance so I'm
我将加入所有可能的我和
going to add up over all possible I and
J对所有可能的结果抱歉
J over all sorry all possible outcomes
是的，所有可能的XI和YJ，所以我
yeah all possible X I and YJ so I'm
在这两个实验中运行六个
running the six these two experiments at
从实验之一，同时
the same time from experiment one the
输出和X从实验到
outputs and X from experiment to the
Y的输出那么PIJ是什么
outputs of Y then what is P I J what
这个符号意味着那就是那个
does that symbol mean that's that's the
在我们的2x2矩阵中，像那个或那个人
guy in our 2x2 matrix like that one or
一个
that one
根据胶合或不那么粘
depending on the gluing or not gluing so
PIJ这是让我说出这是什么
P IJ this is let me say what it is this
这是X的概率
is this probability that X
是XI和第二个输出
is X I and the second output that this
是YJ，让我给我一个
is YJ and let me give me a second
我要记住的例子
example to keep in mind suppose I'm
看着年龄和身高，所以假设X.
looking at age and height so suppose X
是样本的年龄
is the age of the of the sample the
人和Y是我想要的高度
person and Y is the height then I want
我想知道那个分数有多少
to I want to know so what fraction have
一定的年龄和一定的高度是
a certain age and a certain height it's
每一个我都在看着每一对年龄
every I I'm looking at every pair age
身高11岁，身高4英尺
and height age 11 height four feet age
12身高5英尺11岁身高4
12 height five feet age 11 height four
每个组合五英尺，所以pIJ是
five feet each combination so pIJ is the
这些都会发生的概率
probability that these will both happen
既如此有什么事情，你只是我我会
both so what could you just I I'm gonna
在这里添加更多但是那个联合
add more to it here but but that joint
概率非常重要，所以我
probability is really important so I'm
会问你更多关于那个假设的问题
gonna ask you more about that suppose
我把这些PIJ和我添加
that I take these P I J's and that I add
在其他情况下，P1J加上P2J加上P3J.
up P 1 J plus P 2 J plus P 3 J in other
我把pIJx'总结给我，所以我就是这样
words I sum the pIJ x' over I so I'm
看着我的矩阵行的行我这样
looking at a row row I of my matrix so
刚才看到的让我问这个问题
what just saw let me ask the question if
我也许我必须把它放在其他地方
I maybe I have to put it somewhere else
什么是什么意味着什么
what is what what means what's the
PIJ总和在眼睛上的意义
meaning of the sum of P IJ over the eyes
这个数量是什么样的
what does that quantity look like so
这是一个概率圣战是
that's a probability pIJ is the
得到某个我的概率
probability of getting a certain I on a
某些J，但现在我包括了
certain J but now I'm including
所有的眼睛，所以我在那里看到了什么
all the eyes so what am i seeing there
什么PJ
what PJ
谢谢PJ，这就是他的J
thanks PJ this is he J that's the
在第二个看J的概率
probability of seeing J in the second
伙计，因为如果我，我必须看到一些东西
guy because I had to see something if I
在第二个看到J我是被允许的
see J in the second one I I'm allowed to
在第一个看到任何东西但是
see anything here in the first one but
我正在添加所有这些，所以这就是
I'm adding those all up so that's the
点
point
这些会被称为在边缘人
those would be called the marginals in
我的矩阵我会加在一起
my matrices I would be adding up along a
行或将上下柱那些
row or adding up down a column those are
称联合的边缘
called the marginal of the joint
概率因此边际将是
probabilities so the marginals would be
个人概率PI和PJ
the individual probabilities P I and PJ
在进行两次实验的情况下
in the case of two experiments going on
与此同时耶就像新
at the same time yeah just like new
今天的想法一切都已经有点
ideas everything today has been sort of
直截了当但不一样好
straightforward but it's different okay
现在我要完成定义
now I'm going to complete the definition
这个协方差矩阵所以它正在发生
of this covariance matrix so it's going
是的，我想要一个正方形，所以它
to be it I want to have a square so it's
将来，它应该是这样的
going to be and and it should be this is
漂亮x和x的平均值意味着一个我
pretty X and the mean of x mean one I
可以把它称为x和y的平均值
could call it a mean of x and y the
距Y平均值的距离
distance from the mean of Y times so
这将是列时间相同的行
it's going to be column times a row same
X减XY减去均值的平均值
X minus the mean of X Y minus the mean
YXIYJ
of Y X I Y J
所以你能不能看看这个公式
so can can you look at this formula so
这是两个两个实验两个
this is with two two experiments two
实验两个硬币来实验我
experiments two coins to experiment I
得到一个2乘2的矩阵，每个人都看到了
get a 2 by 2 matrix everybody sees that
列乘以2乘2矩阵和
a column times a row 2 by 2 matrix and
让我们只看到这将是一个一个
let's just see what would be the one one
在那个矩阵中输入将会是什么
entry in that matrix what what will in
这是协方差矩阵，那是什么
this is the covariance matrix so what is
在那个矩阵中的一个条目所以
the one one entry in that matrix so the
一个条目来自那个时代
one one entry is coming from that times
这是事情的平方时间
that which is that thing squared times
所有PIJ的这些加起来你是什么
all the P IJ's add them up what do you
我认为我得到了变化
think I get for that I get the variance
X实验的标准
of the X experiment the standard
因此VI有X实验的方差
variance of the X experiment so V I have
告诉你V现在有什么V这个
to tell you what V is now there V this
是V2乘2矩阵在这里我得到了
is V 2 by 2 matrix up here I get the
X实验的方差我该怎么做
variance of the X experiment what do I
在这里得到Y的方差
get down here the variance of the Y
单独进行实验，因为它是明智的x
experiment by itself because it's wise x
明智的，让我这样进入
wise that give me the to to entry so
这只是SigmaY平方SigmaY.
this is just Sigma Y squared Sigma Y
方可以，但新奇是1/2和
square ok but the novelty is the 1/2 and
它是对称的，所以它是对称的
it'll be symmetric so it's a symmetric
矩阵所以这是V转置我只是我们
matrix so this is V transpose I just we
必须看到这里，所以我已经IJ倍了
have to see here so I've p IJ times the
这家伙的距离超过这个家伙
distance of this guy times this guy
这就是将要出现的内容
that's what's going to show up in the
1/2位置它将在第1行中
1/2 position it'll be in row 1 that'll
在第2列中，它就是X
be in column 2 it's the X it's the
距离那么那么会是什么的
distances so so what will it be in the
脱胶硬币独立硬币的情况
case of unglued coins independent coins
0我的意思是我只是感觉像我一样
0 I mean I was just feeling like 0 I
还没有完成计算
haven't done the computation
但我知道，当我独立时
but I know that when I have independent
实验那么这其中的协方差
experiments then this covariance which
每个人都会写作SigmaXY和
everybody would write as Sigma X Y and
在这里它是对称的Sigma
it's the same here it's symmetric Sigma
YX如果你喜欢那些那些
YX if you like so that those those
下标告诉我总和
subscripts are telling me that the sum
豌豆联合概率次数
of the peas joint probabilities times
X从它的距离意味着
the distance of X from its mean the
Y与其平均值的距离加起来
distance of Y from its mean added up
所有可能性都是如此
over all the possibilities so the case
在独立的情况下脱胶硬币
of unglued coins in case of independent
在那种情况下那些是0可能是
ones in that case those are 0 may be
值得写出你想的
worth just writing that out you would
得到0所以你有一个对角矩阵
get 0 so you have a diagonal matrix the
对角矩阵就是这样
diagonal matrix is just the very
单独的差异，因为这就是全部
separate variances because that's all
两个独立的实验是
the two independent experiments are
独立，所以你真的可以期待
independent so all you can really expect
信息是Sigmax平方和
to information is Sigma x squared and
西格玛Y平方，但如果这两个硬币
Sigma Y squared but if the two coins are
粘在一起然后如果两个
glued together then what if the two
硬币粘在一起很好让我
coins are glued together well let me
只是说因为时间到了
just say cuz time is up
如果这两个矩阵将是单数
this matrix will be singular if the two
硬币粘在一起，这将是
coins were glued together this would be
这里的决定因素是0
the determinant would be 0 here the
胶合情况下的SigmaXY将是
Sigma XY in the glued case would be
平方将与西格玛相同
squared would would be the same as Sigma
x平方西格玛Y平方实际上我们是
x squared Sigma Y square actually we're
可能得到所有这一个季度
probably getting all these 1 quarters
并且那将是有道理的
and and that would make sense so the the
如此，我们就这样结束了
case of a so we just end with this
声明这个矩阵是积极的
statement this matrix is positive
半定的总是正半
semi-definite always positive semi
确定总是因为它是专栏
definite always because it's column
时间行我们知道这是正半
times row we know that's positive semi
明确的，它乘以数字
definite and it's multiplied by numbers
更大等于0所以它是一个组合
greater equals 0 so it's a combination
Rank1正半定的所以它是
of Rank 1 positive semi definite so it's
正
positive
它是半定的或肯定的
semi-definite or positive definite it's
肯定是肯定的
certainly positive definite in the
独立的情况，它的对角线和
independent case when it's diagonal and
硬币完全依赖的情况
totally dependent case when the coins
完全粘在一起即会
are completely stuck together that will
当这些是半确定的情况
be the semi definite case when these
条目实际上都是相同的
entries would all be the same actually
所以这是第一次看协方差
so so that's a first look at covariance
矩阵是第一个引入张量的矩阵
matrices a first it brought in tensors
它带来了联合概率它
it brought in joint probabilities it
引入列时间行
brought in column times row
它保持了我们认可的对称带
it kept symmetry band we recognized
正定或正半
positive definite or positive semi
定
definite
所以在部分硬币之间
so in between coins that were partly
胶合部分独立但不是
glued partly independent but not
然后完全独立的实验
completely independent experiments then
这个数字会更小
this number would be smaller the
决定因素将是这不会
determinant would be this wouldn't be
零，但它会小于这些
zero but it would be smaller than these
数字是的没关系
numbers yeah okay
我们跑了四分钟就过去了
we're run four minutes over you're very
善意的说有一个美好的休息
kind to say so have a wonderful break
and I'll see you a week from Monday good
我会从星期一见到你好一周
谢谢
thanks